Phoenix Lai

About

Full-Stack Web Developer with a focus on frontend after 4+ years of experience in the design industry. I strive to remove the language barrier between developer and designer, resulting in a fluid and user centered product development process. I also love to bring unique perspectives and ideas for more creative solutions.

Contact



phoenixlai833@gmail.com



phoenixlai.dev



github.com/phoenixlai833



linkedin.com/in/phoenix-lai

Skills

JavaScript MySQL/NoSQL HTML Agile/SCRUM

CSS Figma

React Adobe Creative Suite

Node.js UX/UI Git REST APIs

Vue Reponsive Design PHP Jest Unit Testing

Education

British Columbia Institute of Technology

2021 - Present

Full-Stack Web Development

Pratt Institute

2014 - 2018

Bachelors of Industrial Design

Projects

LocalToMe | BCIT Interdisciplinary Project

Vancouver, BC

Sep 2022 - Nov 2022

A React app using Next.js that locates and provides low-income families and individuals with free or accessible food resources near their area.

- Authenticated users with Next Auth, stored all users CRUD operations in Firebase, and connected to the City of Vancouver's API to get the most up to date information for food banks
- Used collaborative tools such as trello, miro, figma and github to effectively communicate in a team of development and design students

Evolve Site | Evolve Branding

Vancouver, BC

Aug 2022 - Oct 2022

New site for Evolve Branding which will live as an extension for their EvolveX app ecosystem.

- Learned Flutter within a week and built a majority of the site pages and features
- Designed new features as needed and implemented them on approval.

Experience

Front-End Developer Intern | Evolve Branding

Vancouver, BC

Jun 2022 - Nov 2022

Communicated with clients to deliver on their web needs and developed internal material for the agency.

- Collaborated with other developers remotely via Github, Slack and Discord, with regular stand ups with stakeholder for progress reports
- Responsible for taking ideas from the design to development stage, adjusting according to client needs
- Learned new technologies such as Flutter and Firebase in a short amount of time to take on more complex projects

Experiential Designer | BMF Media

New York, NY

Aug 2019 - May 2021

Created digital and physical visuals from strategy to launch phase for experiential marketing campaigns spanning from tech to fashion and more.

- Incorporated intersections of art and technology with tools such as augmented reality and projection mapping
- Collaborated with various stakeholders to ensure that projects are delivered on time, within scope and budget
- Delivered account winning pitch decks with the design team

Experiential Designer | Rise & Set Agency

New York, NY

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019

Designed immersive experiences for brands in the luxury space.

- Built mock ups and fabrication specs with CAD software for visualization of the user journey and event construction
- Evaluated production costs with producers to determine the feasibility of designs and adjusted accordingly